<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0x157</title>
    <link>https://0x157.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 0x157</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://0x157.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to yet another cybersecurity blog!</title>
      <link>https://0x157.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0x157.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>#cybersecurity #forensics #linux
 I am a 18-year-old cybersecurity enthusiast with a keen interest in digital forensics, incident response, and malware analysis. I am thrilled to welcome you to my cybersecurity blog, where I share my knowledge, experience, and insights about various aspects of cybersecurity.
As a member of the L3ak CTF team, I am an active participant in Capture The Flag tournaments, which are competitive events that challenge participants to solve security-related problems and puzzles.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;#cybersecurity #forensics #linux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a 18-year-old cybersecurity enthusiast with a keen interest in digital forensics, incident response, and malware analysis. I am thrilled to welcome you to my cybersecurity blog, where I share my knowledge, experience, and insights about various aspects of
cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a member of the L3ak CTF team, I am an active participant in Capture The Flag
tournaments, which are competitive events that challenge participants
to solve security-related problems and puzzles. With our team&amp;rsquo;s high ranking,
Im always eager to tackle new challenges and learn from my experiences,
both successes and failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my blog, I aim to provide valuable information and practical tips
to help individuals and organizations stay secure in an increasingly digital world.
I will share my thoughts on the latest cybersecurity trends, news,
and technologies, as well as my own experiences in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git.io/typing-svg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://readme-typing-svg.herokuapp.com?font=Fira+Code&amp;amp;weight=700&amp;amp;size=22&amp;amp;duration=3000&amp;amp;pause=500&amp;amp;color=84A0FF&amp;amp;width=435&amp;amp;lines=%3E+Once+again+Welcome+%3C3&#34; alt=&#34;Typing SVG&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
